Hello
大家好
I am He Zhi
我是何智
the web-based media production team leader from China Mobile Migu Company. slide-2
来自中国移动咪咕公司，是web媒体制作团队的负责人 Slide-2
Today, I would like to share the application of Migu web editing technology in live and post production for sports broadcasting. slide-3
今天，我想与大家分享咪咕在体育直播和后期制作中使用的web编辑技术 Slide-3
During the UEFA Euro2020
在2020年欧洲杯 6.
and the Tokyo2020
和东京2020奥运会 7.
web-based technologies have been largely deployed for live and post production.
基于web技术大多数用于现场和后期制作 8.
The application tools are mainly divided into three categories,
应用工具主要分为三类：
live broadcast and streaming,
直播和流媒体
post production and editing,
后期制作和编辑
and AI enhanced production. 12-p
AI提高了制作效率 12-p
These tools are implemented based on HTML5 and ffmpeg technology.
这些工具是基于HTML5和ffmpeg技术实现的
The below tables list used protocols and technologies. slide-4
下面表格列出了使用的协议和技术 slide-4
OK, let us look at the live broadcast editing tool. The favorite function is to strip and publish.
那么，让我们看看直播编辑工具。最擅长的功能是广播和发布
In order to produce and publish video within 30s,
为了在30秒内制作和发布视频
we have made lots of improvements. 17-p
我们已经做了很多改进 17-p
First, uniformly recode live stream as HLS with ffmpeg,
首先，使用ffmpeg将直播流统一编码为HLS
and slice each ts file within 2 seconds;
并在2秒内对每个ts文件进行分割
The second is to quickly compress 720p low bit stream for web browsing and editing;
第二种是快速压缩720p低比特率，用于网页浏览和编辑
Third, provide key frame pictures,
第三，提供关键帧图片
which are displayed by DOM on the operation track to facilitate interception and location;
通过DOM在操作上显示，便于截取和定位
Fourth, add video JS playback object to quickly browse the content after simulated strip removal;
第四，添加video.js播放对象，去快速浏览内容，在去掉模拟广播后
Fifth, use background services for parallel processing to improve performance;
第五，使用后台服务去同时处理，以提高性能
Sixth, CDN cache is used. 25-p
第六，使用CDN缓存 25-p
And there is still an ongoing issue, which is,
还有一个一直存在的问题
there are two video JS objects with two play windows,
有两个播放窗口，播放两个的 video.js 对象
both need to download m3u8 files.
两者都需要下载 m3u8 文件
We hope that they can share data to avoid repeated
我们希望他们能够共享数据，避免重复
downloading and save network bandwidth,
下载并节省网络带宽
so that we can open more windows and preview the contents in different periods at the same time. slide-5
这样，我们可以打开更多的窗口，同时预览不同时间的内容 slide-5
OK, let us turn to the post editing.
然后，让我们转到后期编辑
It could be regarded as an upgrade of live editing tool.
它可以被视为一个实时编辑工具的升级
Here we no longer pursue timeliness, but professionalism. 34-p
在这里，我们追求的不再是时效性，而是专业性 34-p
We need control different types of content through complex multi-track object and display them by canvas.
我们需要通过复杂的多视频对象，控制不同类型的内容，在canvas上 显示它们
The difficulty here lies in the processing performance and efficiency.
这里的难点在于处理性能和效率
How to achieve? 37-p
如何做到这一点 37-p
Firstly, for the whole architecture,
首先，对于整个架构
it keeps the way of web simulating with final processing by media services to reduce the web load.
它采用 WebGL 模拟，通过媒体服务进行最终处理，减少 web 负载
Secondly, we try to control the window resolution of the displayed content at 480 * 270.
其次，我们尝试将显示内容的窗口分辨率控制在480*270
This is because rendering special effect at high resolution by WebGL takes ordinary laptop 80% CPU;
这是因为 WebGL 渲染高分辨率特效处理，需要占用普通笔记本电脑80%的CPU
Thirdly, in order to preview content without delay by mouse hover,
第三，为了通过鼠标移动不延迟地预览内容
we recode content as HLS with ffmpeg during uploading;
在上传过程中，我们使用ffmpeg将内容重新编码为HLS
Finally, there are some operation optimization points,
最后，还有一些操作优化点
such as providing a small H5 editing window for users to preprocess and cut the required content when uploading. 45-p
例如提供一个小的H5编辑窗口，供用户在上传时预处理和剪切所需内容 45-p
We have tried to implement with Webcodecs,
我们已经试着使用 Webcodecs 来实现
which is very convenient, but it needs to be processed frame by frame.
它是非常方便，但需要逐帧处理
I have to say, it is not very friendly to locate and clip content.
不得不说，对定位和剪辑内容来说，不是很友好
The easy way is webassembly + ffmpeg.
最简单的方法是使用 ffmpeg 进行 WebAssembly
We expect that webcodecs could support more such kinds of functions. slide-6
我们希望 WebCodecs 能够支持更多这样的功能 slide-6
OK, in order to meet the different needs of editing,
那么, 为了满足不同的编辑需要
we have also developed a series of tool sets,
我们还开发了一系列工具
including image editing, cover production, subtitle production,
包括图像编辑、封面制作、字幕制作
video template, horizontal to vertical screen, removing watermark tools and so on.
视频模板、横屏到竖屏、去除水印工具，等等
Due to the web framework and modular design,
由于 web 框架和模块化设计
it makes most of basic capabilities reusable,
使得大多数基本功能可重复使用
and it could easily implement incremental functions. slide-7
而且它可以很容易地实现增量功能 slide-7
On the whole, we choose W/S architecture of the light front and heavy back,
整体上，我们选择了前轻后重的 W/S 架构
which is mainly due to three reasons.
这主要有三个原因
First, there are the performance issue mentioned above;
首先，有上面提到的性能问题
second, for flexibility, light front can be easily integrated into commercial applications;
其次，为了灵活性，light front 可以很容易地集成到商业应用中
the third is for compatibility.
第三是兼容性
Background services can provide API for various terminals on cloud.
后台服务可以为云上的各种终端提供API
OK, we could achieve quickly business integration, strong reusability, and easy expansion. slide-8
是的，我们可以实现快速的业务集成、强大的可重用性和易于扩展 slide-8
In order to produce more content with low cost,
为了以低成本生产更多内容
we add AI functions, such as automatically add label,
我们增加了 AI 功能，比如自动添加标签
automatically add subtitles, automatically remove watermark,
自动添加字幕，自动删除水印
automatically turn horizontal to vertical screen, automatically cut video, and so on. slide-9
自动将横屏转到竖屏，自动剪切视频，等等 slide-9
Finally, let's look back and see why we choose web editing technology for online operation and production platform. 69-p
最后，让我们回顾一下，我们为什么选择 web 编辑技术作为线上操作和制作平台 69-p
Take a media company with 200 employees as example.
以一家拥有200名员工的媒体公司为例
The first is the need of copyright. Through web editing,
首先是版权的需要。通过 web 编辑
we can minimize the risk of content copy, download and disclosure.
我们可以将内容复制、下载和泄露的风险降至最低
The second is the need of operation. Users could save a lot of time by online modification
第二是操作的需要。用户可以通过在线修改节省大量时间
and resubmission the content for operation.
并重新提交内容进行操作
The third is R&amp;D needs. As mentioned above, for better performance,
第三是研发需要。如上所述，为了获得更好的性能
flexibility and compatibility. Fourth, for the cost. Compared with purchasing workstations,
灵活性和兼容性。第四，成本需要。与购买 workstations 相比
web editing can save more than 80% of cost with shared cloud servers;
使用共享云服务器，web 编辑可以节省80%以上的成本
Fifth, the construction and maturity cycle is shorter, which can save 70% of time. 78-p
第五，构建和成熟周期较短，可节省70%的时间 78-p
Online operation and production platform could be used to produce and operate large number of music,
线上操作和制作平台可用于生产和制作大量音乐
videos, and movies and live broadcasts, and plays a core role in the content production system. slide-10
视频、电影和直播，并在内容制作系统中扮演着一个核心角色 slide-10
We are full of expectations.
我们满怀期待
We expect that webcodecs can provide more functions and API,
我们希望 WebCodecs 能够提供更多的功能和API
such as, support video JS object sharing data,
例如，支持 video.js 对象共享数据
support location, cutting media, and support high-resolution special effect rendering with low CPU cost,
支持定位、切分视频，支持低CPU消耗的高分辨率特效渲染
support RMVB \ AVI \ MKV and other common network video format,
支持 RMVB/AVI/MKV 等常用网络视频格式
And support h265 \ VP9 encoding and decoding for ultra-high definition of 4K \ 8K video in the future slide-11
并支持未来超高清 4K/8K 视频的h265/VP9 编解码 slide-11
Thank you, thank you very much.
谢谢大家